A Guide to the A Guide to the Louise A. Hutchinson Papers, 1953-2017
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Louise A. Hutchinson Papers, 1953-2017
The Library of Virginia
51990
7 boxes (4.3 cu. ft.)
Louise A. Hutchinson
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Carroll Johnson, 2017 and Michael Abley, 2017.
Biographical Information
Louise A. Hutchinson (1926-2017) was born in Chicago, Illinois, where she lived in the Irving Park neighborhood until 1966. Hutchinson graduated from Schurz High School and attended Blackburn College in Carlinville, Illinois and later received a bachelor's from the University of Iowa. After earning her degree, Hutchinson worked for WHBF radio station, worked as a reporter for the Northwest Times, a weekly newspaper on Chicago's Northwest Side, before joining the Chicago Tribune. At the beginning of Hutchinson's time at the Tribune, she covered a variety of topics, including a 1957 concert by Elvis Presley, local businesses, and a series of articles on the Brookfield Zoo. In November 1963, Hutchinson was moved to Washington, to cover the aftermath of John F. Kennedy's assassination, with particular emphasis on Jacqueline Kennedy. Hutchinson officially joined the Tribune's Washington bureau in 1966, where she covered the presidencies of Lyndon B. Johnson and Richard Nixon, including the latter's 1972 trip to the Soviet Union. Other notable articles include Hutchinson's 1967 ride to the bottom of the ocean in the Navy's "Alvin" submarine and her 1971 trip to the South Pole, where she become the first woman to stay there overnight. After leaving the Tribune in 1973, Hutchinson worked as he public information office for the Department of Justice's civil rights division. From 1985 until 1991, Hutchinson worked as the director of public information for the National Association of Children's Hospitals in Alexandria, Virginia. Hutchinson moved to Williamsburg in 1993, where she lived until her death in 2017.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1953-2017, of Louise A. Hutchinson are primarily comprised of newspaper clippings of her work from the Chicago Tribune. The newspaper clippings span the entire length of her time working at the Tribune, from 1953-1973, and include articles written by Hutchinson about animals, Alvin the Submarine, Hutchinson's trip to the Antarctic, miscellaneous features and local interest articles from Washington, D.C. and Chicago, school desegregation, and various politicians, including John F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson, Richard Nixon, and their families. Collection also includes correspondence, and several photograph albums and scrapbooks which detail various aspects of her time as a reporter for the Chicago Tribune. Also included in this collection is a 1994 oral history of Hutchinson, conducted by Chicago Tribune reporter Robert Wiedrich, as well as miscellaneous papers and photographs.
Contents List
- Brokers Series, 1961. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1996-2017 and undated. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Louise Hutchinson's Antarctic Album, 1971. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Louise Hutchinson's Antarctic Album, 1971. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Louise Hutchinson's Interview, 1994. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous Papers- "Nice Things", 1958-1967 and undated. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous Scrapbook Items, 1966-1973. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1962. (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Newspaper Clippings- Alvin the Submarine, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Newspaper Clippings- Animals (Not Zoos), 1953-1966. (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Newspaper Clippings- the Antarctic, 1971. (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Clippings- Architecture, 1957-1971. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings- Brookfield Zoo, Eastern Europe, and Black Studies, 1960-1971. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings-Delegate George Grayson, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clippings- Editorial Writing, 1971. (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Newspaper Clippings- Features, Chicago, 1957-1961. (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Newspaper Clippings- Features, Chicago, 1958-1964. (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Newspaper Clippings- Features, Washington, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Clippings- Features, Washington, 1972. (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clippings- Foreign Visitors, 1959-1970. (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Newspaper Clippings- Johnson, the President, 1966-1968. (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Clippings- The Kennedys, 1960-1968. (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Clippings- Lady Bird Johnson, 1966-1973. (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Newspaper Clippings- Luci Johnson, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Newspaper Clippings- Luci Johnson Wedding, 1966. (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Newspaper Clippings- Lynda Johnson, 1966-1969. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Newspaper Clippings- "Nice Things", 1958-1968. (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Newspaper Clippings- Pat and Tricia Nixon, 1968-1972. (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Newspaper Clippings- Porpoises, 1961-1968. (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Newspaper Clippings- Richard Nixon, 1968-1973. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Newspaper Clippings- Richard Nixon, 1973-1987. (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Clippings- School Desegregation, 1969-1970. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings- Stewardesses, Wesley Memorial Hospital Volunteering, and Chicoland Queens, 1959-1961. (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Newspaper Clippings- Stewardess Series, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Newspaper Clippings- Weather Series, 1972. (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Newspaper Clippings- Welfare, 1969-1973. (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Newspaper Clippings- Welfare Series, Cook County, 1961. (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Clippings- Whooping Cranes, 1967-1968. (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Newspaper Clippings- Women, 1958-1968. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Newspaper Clippings-Zoo Stories, 1958-1966. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Photograph Album, 1957-1963 (original--box 7, folder 1). (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Photograph Album, 1960-1967 (original--box 5, folder 21). (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson, undated. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson, undated. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson and the Nixons, undated. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson and Salvation Army, undated. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson, Pat Nixon, and others (original--box 3, folder 2), undated. (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Photograph of Louise Hutchinson with elephant, undated. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Photographs, undated. (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Photographs of Louise A. Hutchinson, undated. (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Santa Claus Speech, 1964. (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Scrapbook, Antarctica (original--box 6, folder 1), 1971. (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook, the Johnson Years (original--box 1, folder 2), 1967-1971. (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Scrapbook, Moscow Summit (original--box 1, folder 1), 1972. (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Scrapbook, Nixon and Moscow Summit (original--box 2, folder 1), 1970-1972. (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook, Press Club of Washington (original--box 6, folder 2), 1970-1972. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Scrapbook, White House Christmas Cards (original--box 2, folder 2), 1969-1973. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Scrapbook, Women's National Press Club (original--box 6, folder 3), 1970. (Box 8, Folder 5)